Good Morning, Church.
Viewers all over the world, when I say 'Church', I mean you. I mean everyone.
Thank you.
Hallelujah.
We received a lot of questions and I asked my people to bring these questions out
so that we can read them one by one.
After we have read them, we decided to pick from two sections -
one that is very touching.
There is a question concerning the message that is being shown on Emmanuel TV.
It was a man or was it a woman? It should be a woman because you know our women.
They normally want to know.
She was asking, "To learn how to know that God hears us when we pray...".
It's a very funny question.
It's very interesting.
She said, "To learn how to know that God hears us when we pray...".
Think about that.
This is very spiritual.
She said, "To learn how to know that God hears us when we pray...".
Tell your neighbour, "To learn how to know that God hears us when we pray...".
After looking at that question, I will not be able to go through it.
I just want to give you a summary of the importance of this question.
When you are praying - even before you pray - you know the outcome, answer -
it's much greater than blessings.
Our mother that asked this question, please listen to that; for you to know how important it is.
To know that God hears us when we pray
is much greater than blessings, healing, deliverance and breakthough.
If you can hear from God, you will know when to pray and what to ask for.
But today how many of us...
You can't hear anything from God.
Because you say you are a Christian, that is why you pray.
I mean because you claim you are a Christian that is why you pray.
You have seen prayer as a tradition, national anthem; this is the way you see prayer.
Even coming to church, you see it as a tradition. On Sunday, I must go to church.
Not that anything attached to it.
Take note of this question: To learn how to know that God hears us when we pray.
It is much greater than anything.
When you want to pray, you say, "Heal me, heal me!"
No. It is much greater to know whether you will be healed.
"Bless me, oh Lord, bless me!"
There is something greater than that blessing.
If you know God will bless you, it is much greater than the blessing you are asking for.
"Deliver me, Lord, deliver me!"
There is something greater than that deliverance.
To know that God will deliver you is even greater than the blessing.
Tell your neighbour again, "To learn how to know that God hears us when we pray
is much greater than blessing, deliverance and healing".
How many of us know this today?
We always base our faith on our improvement after prayer.
You base your faith on your improvement after prayer.
When you want to pray, you say, "Jesus, heal me, Jesus heal me".
When you are not healed, you say, "I have no faith that is why Jesus did not heal me.
Jesus, heal me. Jesus, heal me".
When you experience little relief, you say, "That is the level of my faith".
Oh my God. If I am talking to you, let me see your hand!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You are having headache. You say, "Jesus, heal me, heal me".
When you are not healed, you say, "No faith".
You always base you faith on your improvement after prayer.
Tell your neighbour, "You always base you faith on your improvement after prayer".
That is it.
You always base you faith on your improvement after prayer.
When you have not improved, you say, "I have no faith; that is why I have not improved".
When you have a little, you are praying you want to meet a customer who promised to give you money.
As a Christian, you now say, "Lord...".
You have been fasting for three days because you want to meet the man who promised to give you money.
Fasting for three days; praying, "Lord, touch his heart".
Now, it is time to go and meet the man.
You just get to the door and he says, "Please who is knocking on the door?"
You say, "I am the one".
He says, "Please I dont want to hear your voice".
You say "Ah, I have no faith".
When you continue to base your faith on your improvement after prayer,
you will soon become unbelievers.
Because that is the trick satan is using now; a common trick today,
a common strategy and tactic of satan.
He has been using it to draw you closer to him.
Each time you say, "Jesus, I am hungry" - instead of you to know that
when He doesn't give you food instantly, it does not mean you are not a child of God.
When He doesn't give you food instantly, it does not mean you have no faith.
But you say, "I'm not a child of God that is why the food is not given to me".
Now because of that you begin to see Jesus in a bad light.
Then, you'll now begin to see satan; you are going back to satan.
This is what turned you to what you are today.
You are what you are because you base your faith on your improvement after prayer.
Tell you neighbour, "You are what you are today because you base your faith on your improvement after prayer".
I can't hear you.
Say "I am what I am because I base my faith on my improvement after prayer".
You keep drawing closer to Satan, and your Christian life keeps going down.
You keep counting how many failures you have in prayer.
I asked for this; I didn't receive it.
I asked for promotion; I received a sack letter.
Now, I am asking God to give me another job; I am jobless now.
By the time you now count the number of failures in your prayer,
you are about to begin to pray to satan.
You go to witchdoctors, spiritualists.
You now believe that maybe you have to do the two together.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You have to do the two together.
You now begin to listen to the voice of your neighbours who say, "Ah, where is your car?"
He is making jest of you. He knows you have a jeep you normally ride to church.
He now sees you with a Bible without a car, walking on the street.
"Oga, where is your car?"
"It is with the mechanics".
"Ok, ok. Because I have seen you...".
For how long will you continue to tell your neighbour, it's with the mechanics.
At the end of the day, you'll open the door, open your window,
look around. When your neighbour is not around, you run.
Your big Bible now turns to a small Bible that you can put in your pocket.
They will not know where you are going.
You are what you are because you base your faith on your improvement.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You now have a small Bible that you can put inside your pocket.
When you do not carry a Bible, your neighbour cannot ask you where you are going.
Sometimes, you wear a T-shirt and put your suit inside (a bag).
I don't want them to know where I am going.
These two issues are very important that the woman asked me.
I know that she is being used mightily by God in asking me,
"To learn how to know that God hears us when we pray is much greater than anything".
If you know you hear from God after prayer, you will not be disappointed
because when you come to Him, He will tell you what you want to ask for is not His will.
We always ask for something against God's will.
If you pray according to His will, you will receive.
Look at me. I am having this.
It is my intention to give it to you.
And you now come to me, "T.B. Joshua, give me". I will give it to you.
But this one is not for you.
You now come to me and begin to pray, "T.B. Joshua, give me".
Ah. It is not for you. If I give it to you, it will destroy you.
If I give it to you, it will terminate your life.
If I give it to you, it will take you away from Christian life.
He will not give it to you.
Sometimes, those prayers are meant to strengthen your desire.
Unanswered prayers are meant to strengthen your desire;
they are meant to stop you awhile in order to prepare you better.
They are not unanswered prayers.
They seem unanswered but they are not.
To base your prayer on your improvement after prayer is nonsense.
You say, "Jesus, give me bread" and you are not given, you feel faithless.
I don't have faith.
And that will not encourage you to continue striving.
Today, we seem to listen to what people complain and pray over it,
instead of listening to what God says we should pray for.
We should listen to God, "In the name of Jesus, this man is asking for prayer -
what kind of prayer will I offer for him?"
But since we cannot reach God and we have no access to God,
we tend to listen to what you people demand for.
You ask for bread - "In the name of Jesus, God, give bread".
"God, give him bread."
Instead of asking God.
This man is asking for prayer.
It may be biscuit that God wants us to give to this man instead of bread.
And that biscuit will contain the bread you are asking for.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If I am talking to you, let me see your hand.
These are the challenges we are having today.
What you do today - "Man of God, pray for me".
Even some of us will go ahead to ask, "What is your problem?"
"My marital life is destroyed."
"Ok. Father, Father, bring this man and this woman together. Let them come together.
What you have joined together, no one should put asunder, in Jesus' name."
No answer because we listened to the patient instead of listening to God.
We cannot order God; God orders us.
But today, we order God.
By listening to the patient - "I have marital problem" - and I start praying over that marital problem,
we are ordering God.
How do we know that this is the will of God for the woman?
We should pray according to His will.
When you are not praying according to His will, you are deceiving yourself.
When we pray according to His will, He answers us.
We need to ask God's will over issues.
You are very poor, you have debt and you run to me,
"Man of God, I have debt, I have no money. Pray for me. I have debt. I have no house".
Now, instead of asking God - God's will over the matter -
and God's will may be, "Pray for the man against sickness",
not even what the man asked for,
that prayer alone will solve all other problems.
But we go ahead to pray according to the man's will.
The man demanded for breakthrough and we begin to pray, "Breakthrough, breakthrough".
You cannot order God; God orders us.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
And we too - members, subjects, patients - you people have constituted temptations.
You tempt your pastor; you tempt everyone because you are ignorant.
What do you expect from an ignorant person?
There's nothing an ignorant person cannot do
because you don't even know 1,2,3 in things of the spirit.
Tempter.
When you just get to your pastor, "Man of God, my business is not moving".
Now, you are a tempter.
Man of God himself - ignorant.
He does not even know how to go about it.
He wants to pray over your business instead of asking God - God's will.
When we pray according to His will, He answers us.
Not according to your will.
Not according to the will of the patient.
This is quiet different from a medical issue.
When you have a problem and you go to the doctor, you help the doctor.
Oftentimes, we help the doctor. How?
You say, "I have a problem, doctor".
He will ask you, "What is your problem?"
"Chronic headache."
Now, you are helping the doctor.
He will now focus on that X-ray to see your head.
But if your doctor cannot find anything, he will still go an extra mile
to check other faculties or organs of your system,
to know where the problem comes from.
If he cannot find the problem, he will say, "Ah, I cannot trace anything now".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Which is quite different from God.
All of us have become a tempter to God because of our ignorance.
When the name of Jesus has not answered, we say, "It doesn't work for me".
And the name of Jesus is alive.
When we call that name and he has not answered us, we think that it doesn't work for us.
Some ignorant people would say, "No, he is not alive. There is nothing like that".
But those who want to be mine will say, "It doesn't work for me".
It means they still believe that it works for some people.
When you meet your pastor tomorrow for an issue, how do you approach it now?
You say, "Pastor, my business is not moving. Pray for me".
You have become a tempter; tempting the pastor.
The pastor too is not supposed to pray over that issue.
He is supposed to ask God - God's will.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Your business not moving may be to preserve you for some days or months.
God can use your business, the slowing down of your business, to preserve you.
He can use the failure of your business to preserve you.
He will preserve you.
If your business is moving and you are travelling all over, maybe something would have happened to you.
Maybe you would have ended your life suddently just like that.
But instead of allowing your business to move and you ending your life,
He will slow down the business so that you will not be able to travel to where satan will catch you.
If I am talking to you, let me see your hand!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If you are destined for Heaven and Heaven is your home, God has a way of stopping you.
Even if you live in the clubhouse 24/7 and you are in the clubhouse dancing naked
and do all sorts of things, and Heaven is your home, He has a way of stopping you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
He has a way of stopping you so that you can inherit the Kingdom.
He can use any foolish thing; He can use anything.
He can use failure; he can even use cancer.
When you dance naked, have cancer and get to the doctor, the doctor says, "This is cancer.
You have seven days left to spend on this earth".
You say, "Doctor, what will I do?" Nobody wants to die.
"What will I do?"
He says, "You smoke too much. Where are you working?"
"I'm in the clubhouse."
"Ah, stop that. Stop smoking. Ok? Look onto God."
"If I do that, I will not die?"
"You will not die. Your life will still be prolonged."
"Ok."
You stop smoking, you stop nonsense, you come back.
When you come back - what kind of cancer? Your cancer is not like others!
Those for whom God uses those foolish things to preserve, their own foolish thing is not like others.
Their own sickness is to kill or destroy them but yours is to preserve you.
Are you getting me?
When I say foolish things, I mean all kind of nonsense like cancer, sickness, poverty
failure, embarassment, temptation.
If you are destined for Heaven and Heaven is your home at last, you cannot lose it.
When you are going astray, He will use anything to stop you in order not to lose Heaven.
Listen. He can use death. You hear of people dying suddently.
Sometimes, He uses death to stop the life of that person.
Whilst that person is about to die, he will say, "God, I am sorry".
He will give the chance to say that.
"I am sorry."
He may give two, three or four days, or even just an hour or second for you to say, "I'm sorry" -
he is going to Heaven.
But you people will be shouting, "Heee, he died at a young age. Why did this happen?
Why should all these things happen? This satanic world! This is it".
Sit down there. You will meet him in Heaven.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Sit down and think about your business, the challenges you are facing now.
It is better that you change.
Heaven is your home.
You say, "My business is not going well" and you begin to attribute it to satan.
Who is satan in your life when you are a child of God?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
My business is not moving. I have debts.
Look at me from up down; look at what's happening to me.
This is an embarrassment. You start thinking that it's satan who is behind it.
Which satan when you are destined for Heaven and you are going astray?
In order not to lose Heaven, something has to stop you
so that you can look inward and do the right thing.
If your spirit is telling you that you are destined for Heaven, let me see your hand.
You will know inside you, the indwelling grace is telling you that you are destined for Heaven.
No matter - you are destined for Heaven.
Let me see your hand.
Rise up!
My lifetime.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
My lifetime
I will give God my lifetime
If I give God my lifetime
He will take care of me
He will never ever let me down
I will give God my lifetime
My lifetime
If I give God my lifetime
He will take care of me
He will never ever let me down
I will give God my lifetime
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You may be seated.
That you have sickness, does not mean you are not a favourite.
Don't ever judge your Christian life by your situation.
In the same vein, don't ever base your faith on your improvement after prayer.
Repeat after me: "Don't ever judge your Christian life by your situation.
In the same vein, don't ever base your faith on your improvement after prayer".
Soldier on - you are a Christian.
You pray and you are expecting something and you are not receiving that thing - soldier on!
That should be the reason why you should love Jesus the more.
Jesus said, "If you honour me when your situation seems to be very hopeless,
I will honour you mightily!"
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Tell your neighbour, "If you honour me when your situation seems hopeless,
He said, I will honour you mightily!"
The SCOAN Sunday Service
When a situation happens ... people around say, "Are you a Christian?
Why are all these things happening to you?"
If in the midst this, you start to honour Jesus and say, "Yes, I am a Christian"
and you love Jesus the more, the reward is greater.
When there is no testimony and you honour Him, you are dancing,
you honour Him even more than those that have testimony - the greater is your reward!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
These are the things satan uses to destroy the life of people today.
Look at the question this woman is asking me:
"To learn how to know that God hears us when we pray".
I have answered the woman: "... is much greater than the blessing we are seeking".
How do you learn this now?
To learn these things - these are the things I am giving you now - the experiences;
what Satan is using on the outside to deceive you.
When you have sickness, he now says, "Aha, he is sick now!"
He is happy.
Do you know why Satan is happy when you are sick?
Because he knows that you will begin to confess him.
How do we confess satan?
We confess satan when we start running to spiritualists.
"Hehehe, no food on the table!" Satan says, "Hehe, this is what I want".
He is waiting. Why is he laughing?
He is laughing because he knows what you will begin to confess.
"Church? No, I am not going to church."
You are confessing satan.
Reading Bible - hm.
You normally pray three times a day. You reduce it to just once.
It is confessing satan.
He knows he is getting to you gradually, gradually, gradually
and he knows that soon, you will turn to him and worship him.
Thank You.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
We believe you have been inspired by the clip you have just watched.
Click her to subscribe to witness more of God's power at work in our generation today
and stay up-to-date with the latest prophecies, deliverances,
sermons and testimonies from The SCOAN.
Emmanuel TV - Changing lives, Changing nations, and Changing the world.